STEVE ONYENEKE

11 Morton Close, Uxbridge, UB8 3WR | +44 7404570716 | <u>bobsarglobal@gmail.com</u> <u>GitHub Profile</u> | <u>GitLab Profile</u> | <u>LinkedIn Profile</u>

CAREER SUMMARY

Full-stack Software Engineer with 4+ years' background in building software solutions to boost business productivity. Experienced in all aspects of the software development lifecycle from concept through to delivery and support. Team oriented and effective communicator in verbal and written English.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software & Platform Engineering Analyst; bp, London

Sept 2019-Present

Assist with the design, development, testing, deployment and maintenance of software applications.

Control of Works App (Flutter/Dart, JavaScript (Node.js), AWS Serverless)

- Reduced manual work involved in processing retail sites' visits by 66% by spearheading the development of a mobile app which handles the access control and real-time visibility of visitors in the retail sites.
- Reduced deployment time of app updates by 1 week by creating an automated CI/CD pipeline.
- Was involved in the full software lifecycle from idea to delivery. Designed the UI/UX prototype using Figma, developed the frontend using Flutter and backend using AWS serverless architecture (API Gateway with Oauth2.0 security, Lambda functions written in Node.js, and Aurora MySQL database).

AI Translator App (Flutter/Dart)

- Developing an Android/iOS application which automatically translates scanned or uploaded document images and generates a PDF of the translated document which can be saved or shared via OneDrive.
- Will reduce the time it takes to manually translate secure documents in image formats.

Mobility Finder APIs (JavaScript (Node.js), Azure Functions)

 Provided new/existing frontend applications with a central consistent access to fuel/EV charging locations by developing a suite of REST APIs using serverless Azure Functions written in Node.js.

Automated UI Testing (Java, Appium/Selenium)

• Improved applications' test coverage and reduced time in writing tests by creating reusable test scripts.

Software Engineer; TeamApt, Lagos, Nigeria

May 2019-Aug 2019

Profectus Financial Software (Java, Groovy, MySQL)

- Reduced the time it took to reconcile bank accounts by 1 day by implementing a software that automates the banks' settlement and reconciliation processes as part of a team.
- Increased reusability of the software between multiple bank clients by adapting the software to run specific business flows using automated groovy script tasks in a business process management engine.

Software Developer; Andela, Lagos, Nigeria

Dec 2018-Feb 2019

Authors Haven Backend (Node.js, PostgreSQL) (view code)

• Developed APIs for the backend of an open-source social platform for writers as part of a team.

Restaurant WebApp (HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node.js/Express, PostgreSQL) (view code) (view website)

• Designed and developed a full-stack food delivery service webapp as part of a bootcamp challenge.

Entry level Go Developer; Resoledge, Lagos, Nigeria

Oct 2016-Dec 2018

Coinbitly Backend (Go, BoltDB)

• Reduced manual efforts involved in cryptocurrency trading by 95% by implementing the backend of an automatic cryptocurrency trading software in Go as part of a team.

EDUCATION

MSc (Computer Science); University of Bath, England, UK

Oct 2020-Present

- Courses: Advanced Programming in C and Java, Software Engineering, Principles of Programming,
 Databases, Foundations of Computations, Functional Programming, Artificial Intelligence.
- Projects:
 - Created a small SQLite database application for managing data with Python (*view app*)
 - Implemented a client/server Chat System in Java using multithreaded architecture (view code).
 - Implemented the standard **Connect 4** game in Java. The winning condition requires 4 discs of same colour to be placed in a row vertically, horizontally or diagonally (*view code*).
 - Modified **Connect 4** to produce **Connect N** where N is passed via the command-line (view code).
 - Involved in the requirements elicitation, design and planning of a library software as part of a team.

MEng (Electrical/Electronic); University of Aberdeen, Scotland, UK (Grade: 2:1) Sep 2010-June 2015

• Courses: C/C++ Programming, Computer & Software Engineering, Web Design, Communications Engineering I & II, Control Systems, Signal Processing, Mathematical Optimisation.

Erasmus Scholar Program; KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden Feb 2014-June 2014

 Selected by my University to conduct my master thesis project based on merit of my academic performance. This involved designing the dynamics and control models of an autonomous mini helicopter.

International Study Abroad; University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, US

Aug 2011-May 2012

• Awarded a scholarship to study abroad during my second year at university. Selection was made sequel to a rigorous screening process which entailed outstanding academic performance and a panel interview.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Proficient: Python, Java, JavaScript, Node.js, Go, Dart/Flutter, Git, MuleSoft, SQL, Scrum.
- Familiar: C, HTML/CSS, React JS, Database design.
- See <u>GitHub Profile</u> and <u>GitLab Profile</u> for personal projects demonstrating technical skills and passion for technology.

CERTIFICATIONS

•	Microsoft OpenHack: DevOps	Issued Sep 2020
•	Amazon Web Services Certified Cloud Practitioner	Issued May 2020
•	Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals	Issued Feb 2020
•	MuleSoft Certified Developer – Integration and API Associate (Mule 3.9)	Issued Dec 2019

COURSES & TRAININGS

•	Udacity: React Nanodegree Program	In Progress
•	Coursera: Java Programming: Arrays, Lists, and Structured Data (Grade: 96%)	Feb 2020
•	Coursera: Java Programming: Solving Problems with Software (Grade: 100%)	Jan 2020
•	edX: Microsoft DAT208x: Introduction to Python for Data Science (Grade: 100%)	Oct 2018
•	Google Africa Challenge Scholarship: Mobile Web Specialist Course	Aug 2018

HOBBIES

• Sports (football, basketball, table-tennis, cycling), Latin dancing (salsa, bachata, merengue).